Let's take a moment to have a final discussion about what is going on here.
下面我们最后再讨论下整个流程
We started with our alpha vector,
首先创建 alpha 向量
which is a vector of numbers that we think will be proportional to future returns.
它是一个由我们认为与未来收益率成比例的数字组成的向量
We want to maximize our alpha times our weights and
我们希望最大化 alpha * 权重
minimize risk as modeled by our risk model,
并最小化风险模型确立的风险
and we use optimization to achieve this.
我们通过优化器来实现这一目标
We also apply several other constraints during optimization,
并且在优化过程中应用了几个其他约束条件
such as a constraint that we are market neutral, for example.
例如保持市场中性的约束条件
But if we apply the market neutral constraint now,
但是如果现在应用市场中性约束条件
why did we subtract the mean from each individual alpha
为何之前在计算 alpha 时
to make them market neutral back when we were calculating our alphas?
还要用每个 alpha 减去均值 使它们变成市场中性呢？
Isn't this just duplicating alpha?
这不是重复工作了吗？
Why not just wait for the optimizer to make the portfolio market neutral?
为何不等着优化器让投资组合保持市场中性呢？
We are using optimization so that we can control risk,
我们使用优化器的目的是控制风险
but it creates a challenge when the optimization
但是如果优化器对 alpha 向量有很大的影响
has a significant effect on the alpha vector.
就会带来问题
If your resulting portfolio is massively different than your alpha vector,
如果最终的投资组合与 alpha 向量差别很大
then all your research and evaluation of your alpha factors up to that point might be
那么这时候的所有 alpha 因子研究
invalidated if the final portfolio weights given by
和评估工作就变得没意义了
the optimizer don't look anything like the original alpha factor.
因为优化器生成的最终投资组合权重已经完全偏离原始 alpha 向量
So, you don't want the optimization to change your alpha vector too much.
所以你不希望优化器大幅改变 alpha 向量
If you find some alphas and the optimization yields
如果你发现某些 alpha 和优化器
a very different portfolio than what you had when you started,
产生的投资组合与一开始的投资组合截然不同
then it's hard to figure out how to adjust the parameters.
那么很难判断如何调整参数
It can be hard to know whether to adjust
我们很难知道是否调整
the risk model or the constraints and by how much.
风险模型或约束条件 并且不知道调整幅度是多少
Your alpha research is your pure expression of expected return.
alpha 研究完全是对预期收益率的一种表示
Any deviation from that is a sub-optimal deviation.
任何偏差都是次优偏差
But you're willing to accept that to trade off against risk,
但是为了与风险保持平衡 你愿意接受次优结果
and you're willing to change the alpha vector to optimize on risk.
并且你愿意更改 alpha 向量来优化风险
But that only goes so far.
但也只能做出这么多的让步
If you end up with a portfolio that is completely far away from the alpha vector,
如果最终的投资组合完全偏离了 alpha 向量
then this isn't helpful either.
那么就没帮助意义了
You've evaluated the alpha factors and have some sense of how good they are,
你评估了 alpha 因子 知道它们的效果有多好
but the portfolio may no longer be following the signals of those alpha factors.
但是投资组合已经不再遵守这些 alpha 因子
So, what that means from a practical perspective is you want to
从实践的角度来说
introduce risk control as early in the process as possible.
你需要尽早控制风险
If you know that you'll use your alpha in a portfolio that is sector neutral,
如果你知道你要在保持行业中性的投资组合中使用你的 alpha
then you should make the alpha factor sector neutral.
那么应该使 alpha 因子保持行业中性
That way, if the alpha factor already looks good given the sector neutral weights,
这样的话 如果 alpha 因子已经能使权重保持行业中性
it has a better chance of translating well from theoretical alpha to resulting portfolio.
那么更有可能从理论 alpha 转移到生成的投资组合中